Guide to the Hazel Traphagen Dole Scrapbook
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Hazel Traphagen Dole scrapbook
1901-1906
SC0680
Dole, Hazel Traphagen.
1 Linear feet
Scrapbook from her student days at Stanford, which includes programs, song sheets, photographs, clippings, receipts, notes, dance cards, ticket stubs, and other memorabilia. Of note are 2 leather postcards pertaining to football games, 1904; notes from Jessie Knight Jordan; and a photograph of Jane Stanford in the 1905 Senior Week Program.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Hazel Adah Traphagen earned her A.B. in physiology at Stanford University in 1905; she was a member of the Kappa Alpha Theta sorority. In 1909 she married fellow student Wilfred Heinrich Dole.
Description of the Collection
Scrapbook from her student days at Stanford, which includes programs, song sheets, photographs, clippings, receipts, notes, dance cards, ticket stubs, and other memorabilia. Of note are 2 leather postcards pertaining to football games, 1904; notes from Jessie Knight Jordan; and a photograph of Jane Stanford in the 1905 Senior Week Program.
Access Terms
Dole, Hazel Traphagen.; Jordan, Jessie Knight, 1867?-1952; Kappa Alpha Theta (Stanford University).; Stanford University. Class of 1905.; Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905.; College students--California.; Greek letter societies.; Scrapbooks; Women college students.
Collection Contents
- Scrapbook
  - Scrapbook, 1901-1906 (Box 1)
  - Items removed from envelopes or found loose between pages:
    - Loose items from p. 4 (receipts, registration cards, note, etc.) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Dance card from p. 4 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Loose items between pages 4-5 (schedule of lectures 1901-02, history entrance requirement instruction sheet, entrance exam for English) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Clipping (from envelope) and dance card from p. 12 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Study cards (from envelope) p. 13 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Petition form, blank (from envelope) p. 15 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Leather postcards (from envelope) p. 21 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Clipping from p.21 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Telegram (from envelope) p. 24 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Note (Rufus Kimball) from p. 26 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Programs, etc., between pages 26-27 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Photographs between pages 26-27 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Invitation (Mrs. Hugh Moran) from p. 27 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Lab fees 1903 from pages 28-29 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Programs and a valentine poem from pp. 30-31 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Leather holder for dance cards 1904 from pp. 30-31 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Note from Jessie K. Jordan (from envelope) p. 31 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Dance card and request to assist with flowers at Mrs. Stanford’s funeral from pp. 32-33 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Envelope contents from p. 34: clippings, programs, letters (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Envelope contents from p. 34: objects (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Note and invitation (Jessie K. Jordan) p. 36 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Loose items between pages 36-37 (dance cards, commencement program, etc.) (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Envelope contents from p. 37: thank you note and Senior Week Program 1905 (which includes a photo of Jane Stanford) (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Note (Jennie A. Long) and loose items from pages 38-39 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Items found between unused pages:
    - Clippings (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Dance cards (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Journal notes (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Invitations (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Kappa Alpha Theta items (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Miscellany (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Programs (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Receipts (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Items removed from Kappa Alpha Theta pages:
    - Clippings (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Receipts (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Notes (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Miscellany (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Items removed from Delta Mu Chi page:
    - Ritual script (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Photograph (Box 2, Folder 29)